<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180609" date="2018-06-09 10:59:54 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>PostDoc position in Face Recognition</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>The Idiap Research Institute seeks qualified candidates for one postdoctoral research position in face recognition.&#xD;&#xD;The research will be conducted in the context of the FP7 European project TABULA RASA ( &lt;a href="http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org"&gt;http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org&lt;/a&gt;/ ) on direct (spoofing) attacks of multi-modal biometric authentication systems, and in the context of future projects. Face recognition has been an active research area for more than 30 years and different systems are now capable of correctly recognizing people's faces under specific environments (near frontal faces and controlled imaging conditions). However, conventional techniques for face recognition are vulnerable to attacks. Generally, two types of attacks are considered: (1) indirect attacks are due to intruders, i.e. hackers, in the system, and (2) direct attacks, i.e. replay attacks (also often called spoofing attacks), when a person tries to masquerade as another one by falsifying data and thereby gaining an illegitimate advantage. Currently, spoofing attacks are a major problem for companies willing to market face recognition technologies and there is a need for efficient, reliable and scalable solutions for anti-spoofing in face recognition.&#xD;&#xD;The successful candidate will be possibly working on the following topics in face recognition: anti-spoofing, robust-to-illumination and robust-to-pose face recognition, adaptive face recognition and heterogeneous face recognition. The research will rely on previous knowledge and software developed at Idiap and in the Biometric Person Recognition team ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;&#xD;The postdoctoral researcher will report to Dr S&#xE9;bastien Marcel ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel&lt;/a&gt; ), his/her responsibilities will include:&#xD;1. Research in the framework of project(s)&#xD;	&#x2022;	Carry out research as stated in the assigned project(s), follow evolution of project&#xD;	&#x2022;	Fulfill project-related assignments (evaluations, deliverables, ..) as requested&#xD;	&#x2022;	Publish results (Favor journal papers and good conferences, Favor joint publications with other IDIAP staff and/or project partners)&#xD;	&#x2022;	If required, participate in project meetings and boards&#xD;	&#x2022;	When appropriate, assume leading role as IDIAP contact point or work package leader&#xD;2. Supervision of students: Help supervise PhD students and interns in collaboration with supervisors&#xD;3. Participate in various IDIAP activities and projects as requested by supervisor(s) or IDIAP management&#xD;&#xD;The postdoctoral researcher should have a strong background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra, signal processing or computer vision, and machine learning.&#xD;&#xD;Experience in one or several of the following areas is required: face detection and recognition (2D, 3D or IR/NIR) and statistical models.&#xD;The applicant should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with MATLAB, C/C++, various scripting languages such as Python and with the Linux environment.&#xD;&#xD;Any applicant will undergo a series of tests including technical reading and writing in English and programming.&#xD;&#xD;The starting date is immediate. The appointment is for 12 months with a possible extension. Salary is competitive.&#xD;&#xD;Applications should be done online &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710103%27%7D"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>mardi, 13 septembre 2011</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>PostDoc position in Face Recognition</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="13_PostDoc_position_in_Face_Recognition_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
