<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180609" date="2018-06-09 10:59:55 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>A second PostDoc position</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>The Idiap Research Institute seeks qualified candidates for one postdoctoral research position in face recognition.&#xD;&#xD;The research will be conducted in the context of the FP7 Marie-Curie project BBfor ( &lt;a href="http://bbfor2.net/"&gt;http://bbfor2.net/&lt;/a&gt;/ ) on Bayesian Biometrics for Forensics and more particularly on a sub-project, called BioX, to develop a toolkit for standard operational evaluations of biometric technologies including forensics. &#xD;&#xD;The successful candidate will be working on the various topics in face recognition: face localization, robust-to-illumination and robust-to-pose face recognition. The research will rely on previous knowledge and software developed at Idiap and in the Biometric Person Recognition team ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;&#xD;The postdoctoral researcher will report to Dr S&#xE9;bastien Marcel ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel&lt;/a&gt; ), his/her responsibilities will include:&#xD;1. Research in the framework of project(s)&#xD;Carry out research as stated in the assigned project(s), follow evolution of project&#xD;Fulfill project-related assignments (evaluations, deliverables, ..) as requested&#xD;Publish results (Favor journal papers and good conferences, Favor joint publications with other IDIAP staff and/or project partners)&#xD;If required, participate in project meetings and boards&#xD;When appropriate, assume leading role as IDIAP contact point or work package leader&#xD;2. Supervision of students: Help supervise PhD students and interns in collaboration with supervisors&#xD;3. Participate in various IDIAP activities and projects as requested by supervisor(s) or IDIAP management&#xD;&#xD;The postdoctoral researcher should have a strong background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra, signal processing or computer vision, and machine learning.&#xD;&#xD;Experience in one or several of the following areas is required: face detection and recognition (2D, 3D or IR/NIR) and statistical models.&#xD;The applicant should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with MATLAB, C/C++, various scripting languages such as Python and with the Linux environment.&#xD;&#xD;Any applicant will undergo a series of tests including technical reading and writing in English and programming.&#xD;&#xD;The starting date is immediate. The appointment is for 12 months with a possible extension. Salary is competitive.&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>mardi, 4 octobre 2011</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>A second PostDoc position in Face Recognition</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="4_A_second_PostDoc_position_in_Face_Recognition_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
