<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Team</title>
    <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team</link>
    <description>A tribute to current* and alumni members from the Biometrics Security and Privacy team at Idiap</description>
    <item>
      <title>Andr&#xE9; Anjos is now Member of Research Staff</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2018/5/2_Andre_Anjos_is_now_Member_of_Research_Staff.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d5a2b080-5bad-42f6-931f-15ac931a65c7</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 2 May 2018 11:40:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>After working several years since 2010 as PostDoc and a Research Associate on face anti-spoofing, vein recognition and other topics in the Biometrics group, Andr&#xE9; has been hired as a permanent member of the research staff at Idiap. Andr&#xE9; will phase-out progressively from the biometrics group to develop new activites at Idiap.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Congratulations to Andr&#xE9; !&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Andr&#xE9; Anjos started studying electronics and computers in 1994, when he joined the Electronics Engineering School (&lt;a href="http://www.del.ufrj.br/"&gt;http://www.del.ufrj.br&lt;/a&gt;) at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (&lt;a href="http://www.ufrj.br/"&gt;http://www.ufrj.br&lt;/a&gt;). He obtained a Ph.D. in Signal Processing in 2006 with a work on High-Energy Physics Particle Detection using Neural Networks. In 2004, he joins CERN (&lt;a href="http://www.cern.ch/"&gt;http://www.cern.ch&lt;/a&gt;), Switzerland to work on the development and construction of the Trigger and Data Acquisition systems of the ATLAS Experiment. His domains of interest are pattern recognition and applied computing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You can follow this link to Andr&#xE9;'s homepage (&lt;a href="http://andreanjos.org/"&gt;http://andreanjos.org&lt;/a&gt;) for more information, his CV and a complete list of publications.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2018/5/2_Andre_Anjos_is_now_Member_of_Research_Staff.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saeed Sarfjoo *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2018/4/6_Saeed_Sarfjoo__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">049fad49-8022-4e54-a208-7925bb455926</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 6 Apr 2018 10:34:33 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from April 2018 to ---.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on secured speaker recognition (ie. voice presentation attack detection).&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project H2020 TeSLA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Seyyed Saeed Sarfjoo received the B.Sc. degree in information technology from Isfahan University, Isfahan, Iran, in 2009 and the M.Sc. degree in information technology from Qom University, Qom, Iran, in 2012. In 2009, he joined Asr Gooyesh Pardaz Co, Tehran, Iran, as a Software Developer/Researcher. His career in this company mostly focused on Persian text-to-speech, Persian speech recognition, and Persian interactive voice response systems. In 2013, he started the Ph.D. in computer science at Ozyegin University, Istanbul, Turkey and received the Ph.D. degree in August 2017. In that period, he was also a graduate research assistant at the Speech Processing Lab of Ozyegin University. In 2017, he joined National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan as a visiting Ph.D. student. In the Ph.D. period, his research mostly focused on intra-lingual and cross-lingual adaptation in HMM- and DNN-based speech synthesis.&#xA0; &#xA0;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;His current research interests include deep learning, biometrics, speech processing, spoofing and its&#xA0;countermeasures in automatic speaker verification systems.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object000.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2018/4/6_Saeed_Sarfjoo__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ketan Kotwal *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2018/4/6_Ketan_Kotwal__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">519cd55c-08c4-46b7-9e2c-a3e24207d15b</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 6 Apr 2018 10:32:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from March 2018 to ---.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on secured face recognition (ie. face presentation attack detection).&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project H2020 TeSLA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ketan Kotwal obtained his MTech and PhD from Indian Institute of Technology Bombay (IIT Bombay) in 2012 with specialization in image processing. His PhD work develops new approaches for multi-band image visualization and their evaluation. His work on optimization-based fusion framework was selected in top 10 papers in the International Conference on Information Fusion in 2011. Ketan is the recipient of Best Thesis Award by the Computer Society of India (CSI), as well as Excellence in Thesis Award by IIT Bombay. He is the co-author of research monograph &amp;quot;Hyperspectral Image Fusion&amp;quot; published by Springer, US.&#xA0;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ketan was a part of multimedia group at Samsung Research India where he developed camera features for Samsung's flagship mobiles. For last 2 years, he has consulted to several companies and startups for R&amp;amp;D problems in image processing, computer vision, and machine learning.&#xA0;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object200.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2018/4/6_Ketan_Kotwal__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- summer 2017</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/9/4_Group_photo_-_summer_2017.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">bee57e98-50ed-4a33-82e5-5aff5f9d6185</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 4 Sep 2017 13:44:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Andr&#xE9; Anjos, Guillaume Heusch, Alain Komaty (down), Amir Mohammadi, David Geissb&#xFC;hler, Olegs Nikisins, Tiago de Freitas Pereira, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Pavel Korshunov (down), Jaden Diefenbaugh, Vedrana Krivoku&#x107;a, Sushil Bhattacharjee, Hannah Muckenhirn.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object005.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/9/4_Group_photo_-_summer_2017.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anjith George *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/9/1_Anjith_George__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dddc4246-ef6f-43b0-b472-64e2ecb93cfe</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 1 Sep 2017 08:25:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from October 2017 to ---.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on secured face recognition (ie. face presentation attack detection).&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project IARPA ODIN BATL.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anjith&#xA0; George is currently pursuing Ph.D. from a Department of Electrical Engineering, IIT Kharagpur, India.&#xA0; His thesis work focuses on image-based eye gaze tracking and its applications such as biometric identification and activity recognition. He has developed algorithms for low-cost eye gaze tracking in desktop as well as wearable scenarios. He has proposed and implemented a novel eye movement based biometrics identification algorithm. In his master's work, he has developed algorithms for driver drowsiness detection in automotive environments.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;His current research interests include Computer vision,&#xA0; deep learning, biometrics, and image processing. He is gearing up to work on secured face recognition where spoofing attacks can be preemptively addressed.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object002.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/9/1_Anjith_George__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Geissb&#xFC;hler *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/5/29_David_Geissbuhler__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ce4b6fb5-abb8-4b0c-be1c-220615f77a09</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 11:57:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from June 2017 to ---.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on biometric face presentation attack detection.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project IARPA ODIN BATL.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;David obtained a PhD in High-Energy Theoretical Physics from the University of Bern (Switzerland). During this time his research focuses on several aspect of String Theories, low-energy effective theories and AdS-CFT correspondance. His PhD thesis, entitled &#x201C;Non-Geometric Aspects of String Flux-Compactifications&#x201D;, focuses on T-Duality invariant effective theories and their dimensional reduction to gauged supergravities. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After his thesis, he joins the ACCES group at EPFL for a postdoc in computational engineering.  During this time his research focuses on Discrete Element Modelling (DEM) of ball mills for improving efficiency of the cement milling process, and also Collaborative Scientific Visualisation in the CoViz project. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Two years later he joins the Powder Technology Group (LTP) at EPFL for assistance in mesoscale numerical modelling in several industry and research projects. These projects include, thermal transfert modelling in fibrous media, sintering dynamics, thermal transport and crack formation in novel porous ceramics for thermal insulation and sintering dynamics for beam targets at the CERN&#x2019;s ISOLDE experiment. Moreover he leads the development of the cemff forcefields database, aiming at exchange of data in the community of atomistic modelling of cementitious materials.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;While David had a variety of research interests during his academic career, he is looking forward extending those towards new horizons by joining the Biometrics group at Idiap with the goal of achieving better security of biometric systems.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object203.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/5/29_David_Geissbuhler__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- winter 2017</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/2/15_Group_photo_-_winter_2017.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">960d3198-53ba-4806-8ea8-bd010cb2cc48</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 16:56:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Vedrana Krivoku&#x107;a, Jaden Diefenbaugh, Olegs Nikisins, Andr&#xE9; Anjos, Amir Mohammadi, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Sushil Bhattacharjee, Teodors Eglitis, Hannah Muckenhirn, Pavel Korshunov, Tiago de Freitas Pereira, Alain Komaty and Guillaume Heusch.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object003.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2017/2/15_Group_photo_-_winter_2017.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vedrana Krivoku&#x107;a *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/11/2_Vedrana_Krivokuca___2.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">61678d82-dbe7-47cc-8364-96a47bd69002</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 2 Nov 2016 09:53:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Jan 2017 to ---.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on biometric template protection.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project Biometrics Center.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vedrana Krivoku&#x107;a is joining the biometrics group at Idiap in January 2017 as a postdoc in biometric template protection.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vedrana obtained her PhD in Computer Systems Engineering from the University of Auckland (New Zealand) in 2015. Her thesis, entitled &#x201C;Fingerprint Template Protection using Compact Minutiae Patterns&#x201D;, proposes a novel approach for securing fingerprint templates when they are stored in a central database. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Vedrana&#x2019;s main research interests include biometric security (with a particular focus on biometric template protection), information theory, pattern recognition, and image processing. She is looking forward to joining forces with Idiap&#x2019;s talented researchers to find new and better ways of safeguarding people&#x2019;s security and privacy in our interconnected world.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object003_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/11/2_Vedrana_Krivokuca___2.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- summer 2016</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/8/3_Group_photo_-_summer_2016.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f1c74054-ec0e-4ab3-8bea-c54a2388f1d1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 3 Aug 2016 17:44:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Tiago de Freitas Pereira, Olegs Nikisins, Hannah Muckenhirn, Sushil Bhattacharjee, Teodors Eglitis (down), S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Pavel Korshunov (down), Guillaume Heusch, Alain Komaty, Amir Mohammadi and Andr&#xE9; Anjos.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object002_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/8/3_Group_photo_-_summer_2016.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teodors Eglitis</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/2/22_Olegs_Nikisins__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dfb4e9f1-fb96-42b4-8682-01dd6f6cc015</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 07:57:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from June 2016 to Mar 2017.&lt;br/&gt;Intern on vein biometric recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project BIOWAVE.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Teodors Eglitis obtained an MSc degree in electronics from Riga Technical University, Riga, Latvia in 2014. For his master thesis &#x201C;Development of techniques for system with palm biometric feature extraction facilities&#x201D; he developed palm&#x2019;s vein and crease detection filters for a bi-modal biometric system. It was done while working at Institute of Electronics and Computer Science. There he worked in Digital Signal Processing Lab since 2011 as electronics engineer and researcher. Teodors mainly worked on the algorithm development for the palm biometric system and their implementation on FPGA. His research interests are in the area of palm biometrics, digital signal and image processing, embedded system design. Currently Teodors is working on his PhD thesis.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object005_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/2/22_Olegs_Nikisins__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alain Komaty *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/2/19_Alain_Komaty___2.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">83dd47e7-3400-4ee2-a29c-2a6c56234684</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 08:28:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from May 2016 to --.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on automatic speaker recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project ODESSA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ali Komaty received his PhD from the French Naval Academy Research Institute (IRENav), in Brest, France in 2014. His primary research where on statistical signal processing, where he studied the performances and limits of the Empirical Mode Decomposition when facing correlated noise (fractional Gaussian noise) and impulsive noise (alpha-stable noise). During his PhD, he has established research collaborations with the American University of Washington and FEMTO-ST Besan&#xE7;on, France.&lt;br/&gt;After receiving his PhD, he worked with the passive acoustics (AP) department of the ENSTA Bretagne, Brest, France as a postdoctoral researcher. His research focused on inverse problems, more precisely on whales depth and range estimation using only one hydrophone, where he used modal propagation theory, time-frequency warping and filtering to achieve depth discrimination. His work was on collaboration with the university of California at San Diego.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object003_2.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/2/19_Alain_Komaty___2.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olegs Nikisins *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/1/26_Olegs_Nikisins__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b8c1a779-8368-4ae2-aeeb-621154eff4ae</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 09:32:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Mar 2016 to --.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on vein biometric recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project BIOWAVE.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Olegs Nikisins obtained his Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering from Riga Technical University &amp;amp; Institute of Electronics and Computer Science (IECS) in 2013, where he  worked as a researcher (2007-2016, IECS, Riga, Latvia). His primary research and development experience is related to Computer Vision and Machine Learning techniques with application to biometrics (&lt;a href="http://bite.edi.lv/"&gt;http://bite.edi.lv&lt;/a&gt;/) (face recognition, multi-modal biometrics, recognition of palm veins and ridges), medical imaging and other industry oriented tasks. &lt;br/&gt;After receiving a PhD Olegs carried out a research in Aalborg University (AAU, Denmark) in the field of multi-modal face recognition. In AAU he collected a database of synchronized RGB, 3D and Thermal facial images and designed a three-modal face recognition system / algorithm. &lt;br/&gt;Besides biometric-related research Olegs participated in various Computer Vision based projects: segmentation of blood vessels in medical scans of the lungs, recognition of traffic signs, real time recognition of playing cards, design of control system for manufacturing of electronic components.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object002_2.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/1/26_Olegs_Nikisins__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amir Mohammadi *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/1/21_Amir_Mohammadi__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">4338ee2c-f446-4c04-b791-9fab7d99a910</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 09:32:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Jan 2016 to --&lt;br/&gt;PhD on trustworthy face, perioccular and speaker recognition on mobile devices.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project SWAN.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Amir Mohammadi obtained the B.Sc. degree in Electrical Engineering from University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran, in 2011, and the M.Sc. degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering from Ozyegin University, Istanbul, Turkey, in 2014. During his M.Sc. studies, he worked on statistical speech synthesis, speaker adaptation algorithms, hybrid speech synthesis, spoofing automatic speaker verification systems and their countermeasures. He worked at National Institute of Informatics, Japan with Dr. Junichi Yamagishi as an intern for six months in 2015. There, he worked on development of anti-spoofing in automatic speaker verification systems.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/1/21_Amir_Mohammadi__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivana Chingovska</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/1/15_Ivana_Chingovska.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7f7dd50e-484d-4e1f-83fc-899e4739dcab</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:26:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Sep 2011 to Dec 2015.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on face anti-spoofing.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project TABULA RASA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Ivana Chingovska completed her master degree at the Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Information Technology at the Ss. Cyril and Methodius University in Skopje, Macedonia, in 2011. Since 2008 she has been working as a junior teaching and lab assistant and as a researcher at the Digital Image Processing team at her faculty. She has completed student internships at the technical universities in Lisbon, Madrid and Cardiff, working on various computer vision projects.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object006.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2016/1/15_Ivana_Chingovska.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artur Costa-Pazo</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/11/30_Artur_Costa-Pazo.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d296322d-0a7e-4eb0-bbb3-b4433a83a0a3</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 20:25:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Sep 2015 to Nov 2015. &lt;br/&gt;Visiting researcher on trustworthy face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in a joint project with Gradiant.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object006_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/11/30_Artur_Costa-Pazo.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laurent El-Shafey</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/8/28_Laurent_El-Shafey.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2d84dce3-2f2c-4bd1-9f1a-ba918984e2f7</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 16:13:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Jan 2010 to Aug 2015.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on face recognition and then PostDoc.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project BBfor2, BEAT and Google ATAP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After 5+ years at Idiap working on statistical modelling for face recognition, in particular ISV, i-Vectors and PLDA, but also on so many other things, Laurent ( &lt;a href="https://www.idiap.ch/~lelshafey/"&gt;https://www.idiap.ch/~lelshafey/&lt;/a&gt; ) is leaving the team. For his thesis, on a scalable formulation of PLDA, he produced a &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/xbob.thesis.elshafey2014"&gt;reproducible research software package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Laurent is a great team player and one of the key contributor to BOB ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.io/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.io/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) and a main architect of the &lt;a href="https://www.beat-eu.org/platform/"&gt;BEAT platform&lt;/a&gt; -- an online platform for reproducible research in computational science. &lt;br/&gt;He published many papers and obtained several awards for his work (IAPR Best Biometrics Student Paper Award 2014, European Biometrics Research Award 2014, Idiap PhD Student Research Award 2013 and 2015 Premium Award for Best Paper in IET Biometrics).&lt;br/&gt;More recently, Laurent was one of our asset during the &lt;a href="../Research_Blog/Entries/2015/5/29_The_Biometrics_group_at_Idiap_participated_to_a_Google_ATAP_research_sprint.html"&gt;Google ATAP research sprint&lt;/a&gt; with Elie.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;No surprise that Laurent is moving now to Google in Mountain View to work on top-secret stuff -- hopefully not too much secret or not for everybody ... &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Before coming to Switzerland, Laurent received a B.S. and M.S. degree from Supelec in France, a &amp;quot;Grande Ecole&amp;quot; of engineering in the forefront of Energy and Information Science. He next received a M.S. degree in computer science from the Technische Universit&#xE4;t Darmstadt, Germany. There, he did his master thesis in the Multimodal Interactive Systems group headed by Prof. Bernt Schiele, working on Pedestrian Detection on Onboard Video Data.&#x2028;Laurent is going to work on Face Recognition using Invariant Visual Features in the framework of the recent Marie-Curie funded project on Bayesian Biometrics for Forensics.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object213.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/8/28_Laurent_El-Shafey.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manuel G&#xFC;nther</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/31_Manuel_Gunther.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">01cb79da-8bad-4139-8e0c-bcd7e82dd320</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 16:28:36 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Nov 2011 to June 2015.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project BBfor2 and EMMA1.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After nearly 4 years at Idiap working on face recognition, Manuel ( &lt;a href="https://www.idiap.ch/~mguenther/"&gt;https://www.idiap.ch/~mguenther/&lt;/a&gt; ) is leaving the team. Manuel is one of the great contributor to BOB ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.io/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.io/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) and developed the BOB face recognition library ( &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/facereclib"&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/facereclib&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://vast.uccs.edu/~mgunther/"&gt;Manuel&lt;/a&gt; goes to the &lt;a href="http://www.uccs.edu/"&gt;University of Colorado at Colorado Spring&lt;/a&gt; to work with Terry Boult ( &lt;a href="http://www.vast.uccs.edu/~tboult/index.html"&gt;http://www.vast.uccs.edu/~tboult/index.html&lt;/a&gt; ) on a project funded by the IARPA&#xA0;JANUS program ( &lt;a href="http://www.iarpa.gov/index.php/research-programs/janus"&gt;http://www.iarpa.gov/index.php/research-programs/janus&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;No doubt that the expertise Manuel gained over those years in the Biometrics group at Idiap will be useful for this project.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object020.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/31_Manuel_Gunther.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elie Khoury</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/31_Elie_Khoury.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">c142fc70-5c57-40e5-85a6-7d4d9ea92d45</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 16:03:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Aug 2012 to -- June 2015.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on speaker recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project LOBI, EMMA1 and Google ATAP.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After nearly 4 years at Idiap working on speaker recognition but also on many other things, Elie ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~ekhoury/"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~ekhoury/&lt;/a&gt; ) is leaving the team. Elie was also a strong contributor to BOB ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.io/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.io/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) and developed the SPEAR speaker recognition library ( &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/bob.bio.spear"&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/bob.bio.spear&lt;/a&gt; ), was involved in the collection of the Idiap voice spoofing database ( &lt;a href="https://www.idiap.ch/dataset/avspoof"&gt;https://www.idiap.ch/dataset/avspoof&lt;/a&gt; ) and published many papers.&lt;br/&gt;More recently, Elie was one of our asset during the &lt;a href="../Research_Blog/Entries/2015/5/29_The_Biometrics_group_at_Idiap_participated_to_a_Google_ATAP_research_sprint.html"&gt;Google ATAP research sprint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now Elie is moving to &lt;a href="http://www.pindropsecurity.com/"&gt;Pindrop Security&lt;/a&gt; where Elie&#x2019;s skills but also BOB and SPEAR will be greatly appreciated.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;No doubt that the expertise Elie gained over those years in the Biometrics group at Idiap will be useful for his future career.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object012.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/31_Elie_Khoury.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- summer 2015</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/23_Group_photo_-_summer_2015.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">25ae1dac-12f5-4d87-8bff-6ff20375aa83</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 15:47:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Pavel Korshunov, Andr&#xE9; Anjos, Sushil Bhattacharjee, Guillaume Heusch, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Manuel G&#xFC;nther (on the move to &lt;a href="http://www.uccs.edu/"&gt;University of Colorado at Colorado Spring&lt;/a&gt;), Hannah Muckenhirn, Ivana Chingovska, Tiago de Freitas Pereira, Elie Khoury (moving soon to &lt;a href="http://www.pindropsecurity.com/"&gt;Pindrop Security&lt;/a&gt; ) and Laurent El-Shafey (moving soon to &lt;a href="https://research.google.com/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; in Mountain View).</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object004.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/23_Group_photo_-_summer_2015.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pavel Korshunov *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/1_Pavel_Korshunov__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">94d7684c-0bbe-4136-a171-f29b9adcec62</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2015 20:30:29 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Jul 2015 to --&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on mobile trustworthy speaker recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project Google AS.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pavel Korshunov received his Ph.D. in Computer Science from National University of Singapore in 2011 and was a postdoctoral researcher at EPFL, Switzerland (2011--2015). He is a recipient of ACM TOMM Nicolas D. Georganas Best Paper Award in 2011, two top 10% best paper awards in MMSP 2014, and top 10% best paper award in ICIP 2014. He has over 50 research publications and is a co-editor of the new JPEG XT standard for HDR images. His research interests include computer vision and video analysis, video streaming, video and image quality assessment, crowdsourcing, high dynamic range imaging, ultra-high definition imaging, focus of attention, visual privacy protection mechanisms and their evaluation.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object007.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/1_Pavel_Korshunov__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sushil Bhattacharjee *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/1_Sushil_Bhattacharjee__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">33e6f2bf-09fa-472e-85de-026319396a54</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2015 20:20:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Jul 2015 to --&lt;br/&gt;Scientific collaborator on mobile trustworthy face and speaker recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project Google AS and TeSLA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sushil Bhattacharjee grew up in India. He received a PhD from the Signal Processing Lab at EPFL in 1999, on the subject of content based image retrieval. Since then he has held R&amp;amp;D positions at several Swiss companies, where he has worked on a range of topics including information retrieval, video-surveillance, and bank-note processing machines. He enjoys working on computer vision and machine learning applied to various problems.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object026.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/1_Sushil_Bhattacharjee__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Muckenhirn *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/1_Hannah_Muckenhirn__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">67c028d5-7310-4fc8-b356-75b54aaebb74</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jul 2015 15:41:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from July 1 to --&lt;br/&gt;PhD on trustworthy speaker recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project UniTS.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Hannah Muckenhirn obtained a MSc degree in communication systems from EPFL in 2014. She did her master thesis at IBM Research Zurich in the &amp;quot;Novel Signal Processing Algorithms&amp;quot; team for the Dome project. There, she studied the accuracy of the signal processing chain used in radio interferometry. After obtaining her Master's degree, she worked as a data scientist in the industry, focusing mainly on Natural Language Processing and on smart meter data analytics.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001_2.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/7/1_Hannah_Muckenhirn__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guillaume Heusch *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/6/1_Guillaume_Heusch__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d4340549-2270-429d-939e-dcc2e8f60f5e</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 1 Jun 2015 15:44:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from 2006 to 2009 and now back from June 2015 to --&lt;br/&gt;Scientific collaborator on mobile trustworthy face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project Google AS.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Guillaume received a MSc. in Communication Systems and a Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering, both from EPFL in 2005 and 2010 respectively. As a PhD student, he was performing research in Face Recognition at Idiap Research Institute, and he also spent 6 months at Siemens Corporate Research, Princeton, where he worked on medical image analysis. After having graduated, he went to the Netherlands and worked as a R&amp;amp;D engineer at ViNotion, a small company providing custom solutions for video surveillance applications. In 2011, he joined SICPA Security Solutions, where he was in charge of research projects involving image processing, computer vision and machine learning. His current research interests are computer vision, machine learning and, on a broader perspective, the extraction of meaningful information from raw data.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object003_3.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/6/1_Guillaume_Heusch__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pedro Tome</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/2/28_Pedro_Tome.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">126cf6ea-6e58-4f83-b2b2-e41e8119e8d0</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 15:51:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Mar 2014 to Feb 2015.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on vein biometric recognition and vein spoofing.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the Swiss Center for Biometrics Research and Testing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Pedro Tome received the M.Sc. degree in Electrical Engineering in June 2008, and the Ph.D. degree in Electrical Engineering in 2013 from Universidad Autonoma de Madrid (UAM), Spain. Since 2007, he was with the Biometric Recognition Group - ATVS at the Universidad Autonoma de Madrid. He has carried out different research internships in worldwide leading groups in biometric recognition such as Image and Information Engineering Lab from Kent University, Canterbury UK, CSPC - Communication Signal Processing and Control group from Southampton University, UK, or Security and Surveillance Research Group &#x2013; SAS, at the University of Queensland, Australia. His research interests include signal and image processing, pattern recognition, machine learning, computer vision and biometrics. His research background is focused on biometrics at a distance and videosurveillance, using face and iris recognition and he was actively involved in forensic face evaluation.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object024.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2015/2/28_Pedro_Tome.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthias Vanoni</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2014/12/31_Matthias_Vanoni.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">bfd867a5-c175-4515-bab7-754c78bba1f5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 15:56:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Aug 2013 to Dec 2014.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on vein biometric recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project BEAT.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Matthias Vanoni comes from Franche-Comt&#xE9; (France). He starts a PhD on Vascular Recognition. He was a former officer from the French Gendarmerie and obtained a master degree at the French Officer School Saint-Cyr. He is interested in biometrics and his master thesis was about modeling distortion in fingerprint images, under the supervision of Pr. Ross Arun at West Virginia University (USA). He joined the biometric group at Idiap to work on vein biometric recognition under the supervision of S&#xE9;bastien Marcel. In 2015 he decided to create the start-up company Biowatch as a spin-off of Idiap and its biometric group.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object009.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2014/12/31_Matthias_Vanoni.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tiago de Freitas Pereira *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2014/8/4_Tiago_de_Freitas_Pereira__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">34f48dc7-8f11-4b00-b664-96db1c97fa4d</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 4 Aug 2014 16:49:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Aug 2014 to --&lt;br/&gt;PhD on heterogenous face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project HFACE.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Tiago was Bachelor in Computer Science at Institute of Mathematics and Computer Science - University of S&#xE3;o Paulo (USP). As undergraduate scientific activities, he worked in a research project (&lt;a href="http://www2.nilc.icmc.usp.br/wiki/index.php/Principal"&gt;http://www2.nilc.icmc.usp.br/wiki/index.php/Principal&lt;/a&gt;) funded by FAPESP working with text simplification to brazilian portuguese. In 2010 he joined at CPqD and started to work with face recognition in BioModal project. In 2011 he started his masters project at the University of Campinas (UNICAMP) working with spoof attacks in face authentication systems.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object030.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2014/8/4_Tiago_de_Freitas_Pereira__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nesli Erdogmus</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2014/6/27_Nesli_Erdogmus.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">188d33d0-3bbe-48c0-81ca-6ce1fa386a81</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 16:38:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Jul 2012 to June 2014.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on 3D face anti-spoofing.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project TABULA RASA and Swiss Center for Biometrics Research and Testing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Nesli Erdogmus received her degree in Electrical and Electronics Engineering from METU (Ankara, Turkey) in 2005. She continued her education in the same department for M.Sc. Until the completion of her thesis in 2008, she also worked as a research assistant on a TUBITAK project, titled as &amp;quot;3D head model construction by soft/hard tissue modeling via various imaging techniques&amp;quot;. She did her Ph.D. research in the Multimedia Communications Department of EURECOM (Sophia Antipolis, France) and received her degree from Telecom ParisTech in 2012.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object025.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2014/6/27_Nesli_Erdogmus.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- summer 2013</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2013/8/1_Group_photo_-_summer_2013.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7aedc918-2f73-43ac-94c2-934ae4bfa327</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 1 Aug 2013 16:00:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Ivana Chingovska, Laurent El Shafey, Rakesh Metha, Matthias Vanoni, Manuel G&#xFC;nther, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Elie El Khoury, Andr&#xE9; Anjos and Nesli Erdogmus.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object010.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2013/8/1_Group_photo_-_summer_2013.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- winter 2012</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/10/1_Group_photo_-_winter_2012.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">87deaf4a-641c-4cb6-a172-ae45ce95f621</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 1 Oct 2012 16:02:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Andr&#xE9; Anjos, Laurent El Shafey, Manuel G&#xFC;nther, Tiago de Freitas Pereira, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Elie El Khoury, Ivana Chingovska, Javier Galbally, Nesli Erdogmus and BOB on the top.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object013.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/10/1_Group_photo_-_winter_2012.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roy Wallace</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/7/31_Roy_Wallace.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">c76b1e3c-7203-4693-8499-d82c5dce3878</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 16:23:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Aug 2010 to July 2012.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project BBfor2.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Roy completed his PhD at the Speech, Audio, Image &amp;amp; Video Technology lab at the Queensland University of Technology (QUT), Australia. Through his doctoral work in the field of spoken term detection, he has been involved in patent applications, and has performed commercial evaluations of his research. He has also established research collaborations with the Norwegian University of Science and Technology, and Fraunhofer in Germany. In 2008 he enjoyed an internship at Microsoft Research Asia in Beijing, publishing his work there on unsupervised adaptation for speech transcription.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object025_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/7/31_Roy_Wallace.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cosmin Atanasoaei</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/6/29_Cosmin_Atanasoaei.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">75ece3a0-dfe5-4fc3-a4a4-5708c63aa665</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 16:52:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Apr 2008 to June 2012.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on face detection and localisation using multivariate boosting.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project MOBIO and CONTEXT.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object228.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/6/29_Cosmin_Atanasoaei.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chris McCool</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/5/31_Chris_McCool.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">34e5bfdd-e6a0-4879-831f-c74f28765053</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 16:44:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from April 2008 to May 2012.&lt;br/&gt;PostDoc on face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project MOBIO and TABULA RASA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After 4 years at Idiap, Chris is finally going back to Australia where he obtained a research position.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Chris was a real asset to the team, and I will never be able to thank him so much for its great work during MOBIO and more recently for his investigations on Session Variability Modeling, Joint Factor Analysis and Probabilistic Linear Discriminant Analysis.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object022.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/5/31_Chris_McCool.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- spring 2012</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/5/7_Group_photo_-_spring_2012.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">8a136091-2cb7-40c6-8af5-f9b9caa62601</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 7 May 2012 18:27:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Venkatesh Bala Subburaman , Christopher Mc Cool, Cosmin Atanasoaei, Laurent El Shafey, Ivana Chingovska, Roy Wallace, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Manuel G&#xFC;nther and Andr&#xE9; Anjos.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object007_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/5/7_Group_photo_-_spring_2012.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venkatesh Bala Subburaman</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/3/30_Venkatesh_Bala_Subburaman.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3e5223b3-95d1-4308-8936-79e192741bad</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 16:58:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Dec 2008 to Mar 2012.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on fast face detection.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project MULTI.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object231.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2012/3/30_Venkatesh_Bala_Subburaman.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anindya Roy</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2011/11/30_Anindya_Roy.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2ac4a878-9ad4-4b4d-9913-7a1ebafefb9c</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 16:56:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from Sep 2007 to Nov 2011.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on speaker and speech recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project MULTI.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object031.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2011/11/30_Anindya_Roy.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- spring 2011</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2011/5/2_Group_photo_-_spring_2011.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f860a2a9-f331-4769-950b-0f084a857458</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 2 May 2011 18:26:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Christopher Mc Cool, Anindya Roy, Cosmin Atanasoaei, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Venkatesh Bala Subburaman, Roy Wallace, Laurent El Shafey, and Andr&#xE9; Anjos.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object009_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2011/5/2_Group_photo_-_spring_2011.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- winter 2010</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2010/12/31_Group_photo_-_winter_2010.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7c1e524f-b757-4288-8dcc-1eeaa7768d45</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 18:25:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Christopher Mc Cool, Niklas Johansson, Cosmin Atanasoaei, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Laurent El Shafey, Anindya Roy, and Venkatesh Bala Subburaman.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object004_1.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2010/12/31_Group_photo_-_winter_2010.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Niklas Johansson</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2010/12/31_Niklas_Johansson.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">09676b9d-e1b9-458d-899b-e1f3a3d061ef</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 18:21:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from 2008 to 2011.&lt;br/&gt;PhD on model adaptation for face recognition.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project MOBIO.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object028.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2010/12/31_Niklas_Johansson.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Andr&#xE9; Anjos *</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2010/4/5_Andre_Anjos__.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f7dc0823-3f68-4ea0-8e21-b72d21945d2a</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 5 Apr 2010 16:20:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <description>Member of the biometric team from April 2010 to --.&lt;br/&gt;Scientific collaborator and PostDoc on face anti-spoofing.&lt;br/&gt;Involved in the project Replay, TABULA RASA, BEAT, COHFACE and TeSLA.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Andr&#xE9; Anjos started studying electronics and computers in 1994, when he joined the Electronics Engineering School (&lt;a href="http://www.del.ufrj.br/"&gt;http://www.del.ufrj.br&lt;/a&gt;) at the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (&lt;a href="http://www.ufrj.br/"&gt;http://www.ufrj.br&lt;/a&gt;). He obtained a Ph.D. in Signal Processing in 2006 with a work on High-Energy Physics Particle Detection using Neural Networks. In 2004, he joins CERN (&lt;a href="http://www.cern.ch/"&gt;http://www.cern.ch&lt;/a&gt;), Switzerland to work on the development and construction of the Trigger and Data Acquisition systems of the ATLAS Experiment. His domains of interest are pattern recognition and applied computing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You can follow this link to Andr&#xE9;'s homepage (&lt;a href="http://andreanjos.org/"&gt;http://andreanjos.org&lt;/a&gt;) for more information, his CV and a complete list of publications.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001_3.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2010/4/5_Andre_Anjos__.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Group photo -- autumn 2009</title>
      <link>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2009/10/31_Group_photo_-_autumn_2009.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">e3d3bd42-277e-426b-bc12-6edec281624a</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 18:23:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <description>From left to right: Anindya Roy, Guillaume Heusch, S&#xE9;bastien Marcel, Niklas Johansson, Venkatesh Bala Subburaman, Christopher Mc Cool and Cosmin Atanasoaei </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object003_4.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team/Entries/2009/10/31_Group_photo_-_autumn_2009.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <iweb:dateFormat>EEEE, d MMMM y</iweb:dateFormat>
    <iweb:baseURL>http://smarcel.ch/professional/Research_Team</iweb:baseURL>
    <iweb:maximumSummaryItems>40</iweb:maximumSummaryItems>
  </channel>
</rss>
