<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180609" date="2018-06-09 10:59:53 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>PhD position available</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>The overall goal of the PhD position is to develop new algorithms and models for anti-spoofing in face recognition.&#xD;&#xD;The research will be conducted in the framework of the FP7 European project TABULA RASA ( &lt;a href="http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org"&gt;http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org&lt;/a&gt;/ ) on direct (spoofing) attacks of multi-modal biometric authentication systems.&#xD;&#xD;Face recognition has been an active research area for more than 30 years and different systems are now capable of correctly recognizing people's faces under specific environments (near frontal faces and controlled imaging conditions). However, conventional techniques for face recognition are vulnerable to attacks. Generally, two types of attacks are considered: (1) indirect attacks are due to intruders, i.e. hackers, in the system, and (2) direct attacks, i.e. replay attacks (also often called spoofing attacks), when a person tries to masquerade as another one by falsifying data and thereby gaining an illegitimate advantage. Currently, spoofing attacks are a major problem for companies willing to market face recognition technologies and there is a need for efficient, reliable and scalable solutions for anti-spoofing in face recognition.&#xD;&#xD;The doctoral student will investigate innovative countermeasures to spoofing attacks based on pattern recognition techniques and machine learning, but also explore the use of multiple cues, either intentional or unintentional behavioral visual cues (eye blinking, facial expressions, ...), as well as the use of a additional modality such as speech.&#xD;&#xD;The research will rely on previous knowledge and software developed at Idiap on these topics and will be conducted in the Biometric Person Recognition research team of Dr S. Marcel ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;&#xD;The ideal PhD candidate should hold a Master degree in computer science, electrical engineering or related fields. &#xD;She or he should have a background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra and signal processing.&#xD;The applicant should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with MATLAB, C/C++, various scripting languages such as Python and with the Linux environment.&#xD;Knowledge in machine learning, image and speech processing is an asset. &#xD;Any applicant will undergo a series of tests including technical reading and writing in English and programming.&#xD;&#xD;The successful PhD candidate will become a doctoral student at EPFL ( &lt;a href="http://www.epfl.ch"&gt;http://www.epfl.ch&lt;/a&gt;/ ) provided that the candidate is accepted by the Doctoral School at EPFL ( &lt;a href="http://phd.epfl.ch/applicants"&gt;http://phd.epfl.ch/applicants&lt;/a&gt; ). Appointment for the PhD position is for a maximum of 4 years, provided successful progress, and should lead to a dissertation. Annual gross salary ranges from 43,000 Swiss Francs (first year) to 47,000 Swiss Francs (last year). Starting date is immediate or to be negotiated in 2011.&#xD;&#xD;To apply to this position click &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/education-and-jobs/news/new-opening-for-a-phd-position-on-anti-spoofing-in-face-recognition"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>mercredi, 16 mars 2011</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>New PhD position available</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="16_New_PhD_position_available_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
