<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:37:39 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Saeed Sarfjoo is joining the team</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Saeed Sarfjoo is joining the &lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/7D406E27-423E-4685-8800-C4C4791B5191"&gt;Biometrics group&lt;/a&gt; at Idiap in April 2018 as a postdoc.&#xD;&#xD;Welcome Saeed !&#xD;&#xD;Seyyed Saeed Sarfjoo received the B.Sc. degree in information technology from Isfahan University, Isfahan, Iran, in 2009 and the M.Sc. degree in information technology from Qom University, Qom, Iran, in 2012. In 2009, he joined Asr Gooyesh Pardaz Co, Tehran, Iran, as a Software Developer/Researcher. His career in this company mostly focused on Persian text-to-speech, Persian speech recognition, and Persian interactive voice response systems. In 2013, he started the Ph.D. in computer science at Ozyegin University, Istanbul, Turkey and received the Ph.D. degree in August 2017. In that period, he was also a graduate research assistant at the Speech Processing Lab of Ozyegin University. In 2017, he joined National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan as a visiting Ph.D. student. In the Ph.D. period, his research mostly focused on intra-lingual and cross-lingual adaptation in HMM- and DNN-based speech synthesis.&#xA0; &#xA0;&#xD;&#xD;His current research interests include deep learning, biometrics, speech processing, spoofing and its&#xA0;countermeasures in automatic speaker verification systems.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Friday, 6 April 2018</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Saeed Sarfjoo is joining the team</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="6_Saeed_Sarfjoo_is_joining_the_team_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
