<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180609" date="2018-06-09 10:59:45 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText/>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>We extend the Parts-Based approach of face veri&#xFB01;cation by performing a frequency-based decomposition. The Parts-Based approach divides the face into a set of blocks which are then considered to be separate observations, this is a spatial decomposition of the face. This work extends the Parts-Based approach by also dividing the face in the frequency domain and treating each frequency response from an observation separately. &#xD;This can be expressed as forming a set of sub-images where each sub-image represents the response to a di&#xFB00;erent frequency of, for instance, the Discrete Cosine Transform. Each of these sub-images is treated separately by a Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) based classi&#xFB01;er. The classi&#xFB01;ers from each sub-image are then combined using weighted summation with the weights being derived using linear logistic regression. It is shown on the BANCA database that this method improves the performance of the system from an Average Half Total Error Rate of 24.38% to 15.17% when compared to a GMM Parts-Based  approach on Protocol P.&#xD;&#xD;C. McCool and S. Marcel. &lt;i&gt;&#x201C;Parts-based face verification using local frequency bands&#x201D;&lt;/i&gt;. In IEEE IAPR International Conference on Biometrics (&lt;b&gt;ICB&lt;/b&gt;), 2009.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>mardi, 7 avril 2009</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Parts-based face verification using local frequency bands</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="7_Parts-based_face_verification_using_local_frequency_bands_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="389px" height="229px"/>
</content>
