<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="AC642035-7472-45A7-A869-1DFF61502373">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:36:27 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Laurent El-Shafey</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Member of the biometric team from Jan 2010 to Aug 2015.&#xD;PhD on face recognition and then PostDoc.&#xD;Involved in the project BBfor2, BEAT and Google ATAP.&#xD;&#xD;After 5+ years at Idiap working on statistical modelling for face recognition, in particular ISV, i-Vectors and PLDA, but also on so many other things, Laurent ( &lt;a href="https://www.idiap.ch/~lelshafey/"&gt;https://www.idiap.ch/~lelshafey/&lt;/a&gt; ) is leaving the team. For his thesis, on a scalable formulation of PLDA, he produced a &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/xbob.thesis.elshafey2014"&gt;reproducible research software package&lt;/a&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;Laurent is a great team player and one of the key contributor to BOB ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.io/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.io/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) and a main architect of the &lt;a href="https://www.beat-eu.org/platform/"&gt;BEAT platform&lt;/a&gt; -- an online platform for reproducible research in computational science. &#xD;He published many papers and obtained several awards for his work (IAPR Best Biometrics Student Paper Award 2014, European Biometrics Research Award 2014, Idiap PhD Student Research Award 2013 and 2015 Premium Award for Best Paper in IET Biometrics).&#xD;More recently, Laurent was one of our asset during the &lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/9DD03AB6-0131-426A-84A3-62C3C46C2181"&gt;Google ATAP research sprint&lt;/a&gt; with Elie.&#xD;&#xD;No surprise that Laurent is moving now to Google in Mountain View to work on top-secret stuff -- hopefully not too much secret or not for everybody ... &#xD;&#xD;Before coming to Switzerland, Laurent received a B.S. and M.S. degree from Supelec in France, a "Grande Ecole" of engineering in the forefront of Energy and Information Science. He next received a M.S. degree in computer science from the Technische Universit&#xE4;t Darmstadt, Germany. There, he did his master thesis in the Multimodal Interactive Systems group headed by Prof. Bernt Schiele, working on Pedestrian Detection on Onboard Video Data.&#x2028;Laurent is going to work on Face Recognition using Invariant Visual Features in the framework of the recent Marie-Curie funded project on Bayesian Biometrics for Forensics.&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Friday 28 August 2015</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Laurent El-Shafey</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="28_Laurent_El-Shafey_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
