<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:37:22 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Pedro Tome will join the team</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Pedro Tome will be joining the &lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/7D406E27-423E-4685-8800-C4C4791B5191"&gt;biometrics group at Idiap&lt;/a&gt; as a PostDoc in March 2014.&#xD;&#xD;Welcome Pedro !&#xD;&#xD;&lt;i&gt;Pedro Tome received the M.Sc. degree in Electrical Engineering in June 2008, and the Ph.D. degree in Electrical Engineering in 2013 from Universidad Autonoma de Madrid (UAM), Spain. Since 2007, he was with the Biometric Recognition Group - ATVS at the Universidad Autonoma de Madrid. He has carried out different research internships in worldwide leading groups in biometric recognition such as Image and Information Engineering Lab from Kent University, Canterbury UK, CSPC - Communication Signal Processing and Control group from Southampton University, UK, or Security and Surveillance Research Group &#x2013; SAS, at the University of Queensland, Australia. His research interests include signal and image processing, pattern recognition, machine learning, computer vision and biometrics. His research background is focused on biometrics at a distance and videosurveillance, using face and iris recognition and he was actively involved in forensic face evaluation.&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>jeudi, 13 f&#xE9;vrier 2014</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Pedro Tome will join the team</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="13_Pedro_Tome_will_join_the_team_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="317px" height="250px"/>
</content>
