<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:37:33 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>New PostDoc position</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>The Idiap Research Institute ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch&lt;/a&gt; ) seeks qualified candidates for one PostDoc position in the field of automatic speaker recognition (ASR) . &#xD;The research will be conducted in the framework of the SNSF funded project ODESSA (Online Diarization Enhanced by recent Speaker identification and Structured prediction Approaches) in partnership with LIMSI and EURECOM in France.&#xD;&#xD;Broadly, the goal of an automatic speaker recognition system is to authenticate or to identify a person through speech signal.&#xD;Speaker diarization is an unsupervised process that aims at identifying each speaker within an audio stream and determining the intervals during which each speaker is active.&#xD;&#xD;The overall goal of the position is to advance the state-of-the-art in speaker recognition and diarization. Specifically, the research will:&#xD;* investigate i-vectors and deep neural network for ASR and their application to the problem of speaker diarization,&#xD;* explore the use of domain adaptation.&#xD;&#xD;The proposed research is a collaboration between LIMSI (Herv&#xE9; Bredin, Claude Barras), EURECOM (Nicholas Evans) and the Biometrics group (Dr. Sebastien Marcel, &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel&lt;/a&gt; ) at Idiap. &#xD;The research will rely on previous knowledge and softwares developed at Idiap, more specifically Bob toolkit ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.io/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.io/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) and Spear ( &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/bob.spear"&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/bob.spear&lt;/a&gt; ). In addition the use&#xD;of additional libraries for deep learning (Torch, Caffe or Theano) are considered.&#xD;&#xD;Reproducible research is a cornerstone of the project. Hence a strong involvement in data collection and open source libraries such as Bob and Spear are expected.&#xD;&#xD;The ideal candidate should hold a PhD degree in computer science, electrical engineering or related fields. She or he should have a background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra and signal processing. The applicant should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with Python, C/C++ (MATLAB is not a plus), various scripting languages and with the Linux environment. Knowledge in speech processing and machine learning is an asset. Shortlisted candidate may undergo a series of tests including technical reading and writing in English and programming (in Python and/or C/C++). &#xD;&#xD;Appointment for the position is for 3 years, provided successful progress and may be renewed depending on funding opportunities. Salary on the first year starts at 80'000 CHF (gross salary). Starting date is early 2016.&#xD;&#xD;Apply online at:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710179%27%7D"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710179%27%7D&lt;/a&gt; &#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>jeudi, 29 octobre 2015</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>PostDoc position in speaker recognition</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="29_PostDoc_position_in_speaker_recognition_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
