<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:37:12 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>New Internship position</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Age estimation from face images using Multivariate Boosting&#xD;&#xD;Idiap recently proposed and developed [1] a novel unified boosting framework.&#xD;We applied this framework to the several face processing tasks, face detection, facial feature localisation, and pose classification, and use the same&#xD;boosting algorithm and the same pool of features (Local Binary Patterns). This is in contrast with the standard approaches that make use of a variety of&#xD;features and models, for example AdaBoost, cascades of boosted classifiers and Active Appearance Models.&#xA0;&#xD;&#xD;The unified boosting framework covers multivariate classification and regression problems and it is achieved by interpreting boosting as optimization in the functional space of the weak learners. Thus a wide range of smooth loss&#xA0;functions can be optimized with the same algorithm. We extended recent work on TaylorBoost and used an empirical expectation formulation that minimizes the average loss to train real-time models using local binary features. This is&#xA0;achieved using look-up-tables as weak learners and multi-block Local Binary Patterns as features. The resulting boosting algorithms are simple, efficient and easily&#xD;scalable with the available resources.&#xD;&#xD;The goal of this project is to leverage on the developed unified boosting framework and to apply it to the task of age estimation from face images.&#xD;&#xD;[1] Cosmin Atanasoaei, "Multivariate Boosting with Look-up Tables for Face Processing", PhD thesis 2012.&#xD;&lt;a href="http://publications.idiap.ch/index.php/publications/show/2315"&gt;http://publications.idiap.ch/index.php/publications/show/2315&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;The student will be using the BOB open source library ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.com/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.com/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) developed at Idiap.&#xD;&#xD;The student should have a background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra, signal processing, and machine learning.&#xD;The applicant should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with MATLAB, C/C++, various scripting languages such as Python and with the Linux environment.&#xD;Any applicant might undergo a series of tests including programming.&#xD;&#xD;The starting date is immediate. The appointment is for 6 months. Salary is 2000 CHF per month.&#xD;&#xD;Apply online at:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710132%27%7D"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710132%27%7D&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>mardi, 29 janvier 2013</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Internship position on age estimation</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="29_Internship_position_on_age_estimation_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
