<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180609" date="2018-06-09 11:00:17 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>New Internship position</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>The Idiap research institute is coordinating two major European projects in Biometrics: TABULA RASA ( &lt;a href="http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org"&gt;http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org&lt;/a&gt; ) and BEAT ( &lt;a href="http://www.beat-eu.org"&gt;http://www.beat-eu.org&lt;/a&gt; ). In the context of these projects, the biometrics group at Idiap ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html&lt;/a&gt; ) is well-known for his work on spoofing and anti-spoofing&#xD;( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Publications.html#topics:Spoofing"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Publications.html#topics:Spoofing&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;&#xD;Spoofing is the action of outwitting a biometric sensor by presenting a counterfeit biometric evidence of a valid user. It is a direct attack to the sensory input of a biometric system and the attacker does not need previous knowledge about the recognition algorithm. Most of the biometric modalities are not resistant to spoofing attacks: the biometric systems are usually designed to only recognize identities without concern whether the identity is live or not. Despite the existence of very sophisticated biometric systems nowadays, implementing anti-spoofing schemes for them is still in its infancy.&#xD;&#xD;Idiap has explored already spoofing to visual spectra face recognition using printed photos, displayed photos/videos and 3D masks, and developed anti-spoofing methods. In the context of a new funded project, Idiap is looking to explore voice spoofing, as well as spoofing to Near-Infrared and 3D face recognition with depth sensors.&#xD;&#xD;The goal of the project is to collect a novel audio-visual spoofing database for studies in face/voice spoofing and anti-spoofing.&#xD;&#xD;Idiap seeks an Intern student to develop and to setup a audio-visual capture environment, to collect a spoofing database, to evaluate the vulnerability to spoofing of reference speaker recognition systems, and possibly to develop anti-spoofing algorithms.&#xD;&#xD;The student will work closely with a PostDoc researcher and will report directly to Dr S&#xE9;bastien Marcel ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;The student will be using the BOB open source library ( &lt;a href="http://idiap.github.com/bob/"&gt;http://idiap.github.com/bob/&lt;/a&gt; ) developed at Idiap.&#xD;&#xD;Applicants should have a background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra, signal processing, and machine learning. Applicants should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with C/C++, various scripting languages (Python is a plus) and with the Linux environment. MATLAB is not a plus. Any applicant might undergo a series of tests including programming.&#xD;&#xD;The starting date is immediate. The appointment is for 6 months. Salary is 2000 CHF per month.&#xD;&#xD;Apply online at:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710147%27%7D"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710147%27%7D&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>jeudi, 9 janvier 2014</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Internship position on spoofing in face and speaker recognition</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="9_Internship_position_on_spoofing_in_face_and_speaker_recognition_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
