<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:37:22 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>New PostDoc position</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>The Idiap research institute is coordinating two major European projects in Biometrics: TABULA RASA ( &lt;a href="http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org"&gt;http://www.tabularasa-euproject.org&lt;/a&gt; ) and BEAT ( &lt;a href="http://www.beat-eu.org"&gt;http://www.beat-eu.org&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;In the context of these projects, the biometrics group at Idiap ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html&lt;/a&gt; ) is well-known for his work on biometrics but also on spoofing/anti-spoofing&#xD;( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Publications.html"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Publications.html&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;&#xD;Spoofing is the action of outwitting a biometric sensor by presenting a counterfeit biometric evidence of a valid user. It is a direct attack to the sensory input of a biometric system and the attacker does not need previous knowledge about the recognition algorithm. Most of the biometric modalities are not resistant to spoofing attacks: the biometric systems are usually designed to only recognize identities without concern whether the identity is live or not. Despite the existence of very sophisticated biometric systems nowadays, implementing anti-spoofing schemes for them is still in its infancy.&#xD;&#xD;Idiap has explored already spoofing to visual spectra face recognition using printed photos, displayed photos/videos and 3D masks, and developed anti-spoofing methods. In the context of a new funded project, Idiap is looking to explore spoofing to vascular biometrics.&#xD;&#xD;The successful candidate will be possibly working on the following topics in vascular biometrics: mobile vascular recognition, spoofing and anti-spoofing.&#xD;The research will rely on previous knowledge and software developed at Idiap and in the biometrics team ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel/professional/Research_Team.html&lt;/a&gt; ).&#xD;&#xD;The postdoctoral researcher will report to Dr S&#xE9;bastien Marcel ( &lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/~marcel&lt;/a&gt; ), his/her responsibilities will include:&#xD;1. Research in the framework of project(s)&#xD;&#x2022; Carry out research as stated in the assigned project(s), follow evolution of project&#xD;&#x2022; Fulfill project-related assignments (evaluations, deliverables, ..) as requested&#xD;&#x2022; Publish results (Favour journal papers and good conferences, Favour joint publications with other IDIAP staff and/or project partners)&#xD;&#x2022; If required, participate in project meetings and boards&#xD;&#x2022; When appropriate, assume leading role as IDIAP contact point or work package leader&#xD;2. Supervision of students: Help supervise PhD students and interns in collaboration with supervisors&#xD;3. Participate in various IDIAP activities and projects as requested by supervisor(s) or IDIAP management&#xD;&#xD;The postdoctoral researcher should have a strong background in statistics or applied mathematics, optimization, linear algebra, signal processing or computer vision, and machine learning.&#xD;Experience in one or several of the following areas is required: vascular biometrics, face recognition (2D or NIR) and statistical models.&#xD;The applicant should also have strong programming skills and be familiar with C/C++, various scripting languages (in particular Python) and with the Linux environment. MATLAB is not a plus.&#xD;Any applicant will undergo a series of tests including technical reading and writing in English and programming.&#xD;&#xD;The starting date is immediate. The appointment is for 12 months with a possible extension.&#xD;Salary is competitive.&#xD;&#xD;Apply online at:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710148%27%7D"&gt;http://www.idiap.ch/webapps/jobs/ors/applicant/position/index.php?PHP_APE_DR_9e581720b5ef40dc7af21c41bac4f4eb=%7B__TO%3D%27detail%27%3B__PK%3D%2710148%27%7D&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>jeudi, 9 janvier 2014</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>PostDoc position in Vascular Biometrics</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="9_PostDoc_position_in_Vascular_Biometrics_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
