<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="AC642035-7472-45A7-A869-1DFF61502373">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180610" date="2018-06-10 15:36:32 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>David Geissb&#xFC;hler</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Member of the biometric team from June 2017 to ---.&#xD;PostDoc on biometric face presentation attack detection.&#xD;Involved in the project IARPA ODIN BATL.&#xD;&#xD;David obtained a PhD in High-Energy Theoretical Physics from the University of Bern (Switzerland). During this time his research focuses on several aspect of String Theories, low-energy effective theories and AdS-CFT correspondance. His PhD thesis, entitled &#x201C;Non-Geometric Aspects of String Flux-Compactifications&#x201D;, focuses on T-Duality invariant effective theories and their dimensional reduction to gauged supergravities. &#xD;&#xD;After his thesis, he joins the ACCES group at EPFL for a postdoc in computational engineering.  During this time his research focuses on Discrete Element Modelling (DEM) of ball mills for improving efficiency of the cement milling process, and also Collaborative Scientific Visualisation in the CoViz project. &#xD;&#xD;Two years later he joins the Powder Technology Group (LTP) at EPFL for assistance in mesoscale numerical modelling in several industry and research projects. These projects include, thermal transfert modelling in fibrous media, sintering dynamics, thermal transport and crack formation in novel porous ceramics for thermal insulation and sintering dynamics for beam targets at the CERN&#x2019;s ISOLDE experiment. Moreover he leads the development of the cemff forcefields database, aiming at exchange of data in the community of atomistic modelling of cementitious materials.&#xD;&#xD;While David had a variety of research interests during his academic career, he is looking forward extending those towards new horizons by joining the Biometrics group at Idiap with the goal of achieving better security of biometric systems.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, 29 May 2017</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>David Geissb&#xFC;hler *</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="29_David_Geissbuhler___files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
