<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F27D61BF-0911-4E7F-94E4-A327692575EA">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20180609" date="2018-06-09 10:59:46 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText/>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Guillaume Heusch, Chris Mc Cool and S&#xE9;bastien Marcel&#xA0;attended the&#xA0; IAPR/IEEE&#xA0;International Conference on&#xA0;Biometrics (&lt;b&gt;ICB&lt;/b&gt; ) from June 2nd&#xA0;to June 5th . This conference was&#xA0;jointly organised by the International&#xA0;Association of Pattern&#xA0;Recognition (&lt;b&gt;IAPR&lt;/b&gt;) and the IEEE Biometrics Council.&#xA0;It tooks place in&#xA0;Alghero, Italy.&#xD;&#xD;The conference was single track, and we thus had the occasion to attend all the interesting presentations. In addition, a poster session and a demo session were organized each afternoon. Oral presentations were grouped by topics: biometric technologies (face, voice, fingerprint,&#xD;palmprint and gait), but there were also presentations on fusion and competitions.&#xD;&#xD;The conference brought together many experts from the diverse field of biometrics and had three invited speakers: Heinrich H. Bulthoff, Sadaoki Furui and Jean-Christophe Fondeur. The presentation by Heinrich H. Bulthoff on "What Can Machine Vision Learn from Human Perception?" was very interesting as it gave an insight into the depth of research that is possible in a large research institute such as the Max Planck Institute. While the presentation by Sadaoki Furui provided a very nice overview of how Speaker Recognition has developed over the last 40 years. The keynote given by&#xA0;Jean-Christophe Fondeur, the R&amp;T Director from Sagem Security, was reviewing the challenges to be&#xA0;faced for biometrics to be deployed&#xA0;on&#xA0;real-world applications (mainly airports and borders).&#xA0;In particular,&#xA0;he pointed out that&#xA0;research should focus on three main aspects: speed (i.e. being able to authenticate people as quick as possible to achieve an acceptable throughput), scalability (airports are dealing with thousands of people everyday) and privacy. He also presented some of the work done at Sagem, with a focus on hardware, like a palmprint verification machine when you only have to swipe your hand, or an automatic portal allowing identity verification.&#xD;&#xD;Chris presented his work on "&lt;i&gt;Parts-Based Face Verification Using Local&#xA0;Frequency Bands&lt;/i&gt;", and Guillaume had a poster to present during the last afternoon. His work&#xA0;seemed&#xA0;to have been well-received: several people asked questions, on the particular topic of course, but also on the more general framework of Bayesian Networks. It was also an opportunity for him to present his PhD work in a broader way to some of the Professors who were attending the conference.&#xD;&#xD;Concerning the work presented during this conference, the majority was dedicated to face recognition (both 2d and 3d) followed by speech and fingerprint.&#xA0;Other presentations were on the many biometric competitions. Some of these competitions include: face recognition using video, fingerprint and on-line signature verification and the Multiple Biometric Grand Challenge (MBGC).&#xD;&#xD;Interesting presentations (for us) include:&#xD; "&lt;i&gt;Pixelwise Local Binary Pattern&#xA0;Models of Faces Using Kernel Density Estimation&lt;/i&gt;" from&#xA0;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Timo Ahonen and Matti Pietikainen&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;,&#xD; "&lt;i&gt;Challenges and&#xA0;Research Directions for Adaptive Biometric Recognition Systems&lt;/i&gt;" from &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Norman Poh and al.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;,&#xD; "&lt;i&gt;Manifold learning for&#xA0;Gender Classification from Face Sequences&lt;/i&gt;" from&#xA0;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Abdenour Hadid and Matti Pietikainen&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;,&#xD;&#xD;and also more particularly:&#xD; "&lt;i&gt;Minimising Speaker Verification Utterance Length through Confidence Based Early Verification Decisions&lt;/i&gt;" &#xA0;from &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;R. Vogt and S. Sridharan&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&#x2028;&#x2028;The general outline of this paper is to estimate (on a short length of speech) the confidence of the score for the speaker. This means that rather than waiting for a fixed-length of speech to obtain a decision the process can stop when the system is confident that the acceptance score/threshold has been reached. This is done by estimating confidence intervals on the expected log-likelihood ratio.&#xD;&#xD; and "&lt;i&gt;Multi-Region Probabilistic Histograms for Robust and Scalable Identity&#xA0;Inference&lt;/i&gt;" from &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;C. Sanderson and B. Lovell&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&#x2028;&#x2028;Conrad presented a system to perform efficient face verification. He uses as a basis the GMM Parts-Based technique, however, he uses this to get an initial background model which is then considered to be a dictionary of words (face-parts essentially); the mean of each component of the UBM GMM is considered to be a visual (face) word. The dictionary is then used to develop a model for each user. In the end rather than developing a GMM for each user a histogram can be derived and used to score each client quickly and efficiently.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>mercredi, 17 juin 2009</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>International Conference on Biometrics (ICB) 2009</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="17_International_Conference_on_Biometrics_%28ICB%29_2009_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="356px" height="275px"/>
</content>
